RENAE SOWALD

Bothell, WA 98012 937-902-8398 | renaesowald@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/renae-sowald | https://github.com/rsowald

SUMMARY

I am a tech company jack-of-all-trades. In June 2021, I completed a full-stack coding boot camp, and was confident that I would work as a full-stack or front-end developer. However, during my job search, I discovered that there were many other jobs that joined my academic strength of clear and concise writing with my new developer skills. Over the last 3 years, I gained real-world experience as a technical writer at start-up tech companies. The pace of development and releases was fast, and I often had to adapt to wear multiple hats. In my last two positions, I worked closely with Marketing and Engineering, contributing content and feedback to projects from social media copy and blogs to technical reference and code walkthrough guides. Unfortunately, in July 2024, my latest employer had to downsize half of its employees. I have since been running my school's PTA and art program. In any role, I enjoy learning new tools, solving problems, and delivering quality results. I feel that I could be a passionate, collaborative, and constructive member of a technical writing team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, ES6, HTML 5, CSS 3, NodeJS, SQL (MySQL), NoSQL (Mongo) **Libraries and Applications:** npm, Materialize, Bootstrap, Handlebars.js, Sequelize, Mongoose,

Express, Heroku, React.js, Next.js, Vue, Vite, Swagger, Docker, Docusaurus

Creative Tools: PowerPoint, Canva, Paint

Concepts: MVC, responsive design, agile methodologies

Spoken Languages: English, Spanish, German

EXPERIENCE

Frank Love Elementary, Bothell, WA – PTA President & Art Docent Coordinator AUG 2022 - Current

- Given an art project idea, I created monthly PowerPoint presentations walking through the project with an art history and theory lesson built in.
- Created copious flyers that were both informative and aesthetically pleasing using Canva.
- Hosted monthly public meetings, set and managed a sizable budget, and conformed to all legal and organizational requirements.
- Managed around 15 active members at a time, acting as point of contact for all committees.
- Ran point on at least 3 community events yearly, including volunteer or vendor coordination, setup, communications, and budgeting.

Event Store, Bothell, WA – *Technical Documentation Writer*

AUGUST 2023 - JULY 2024

- Edited existing documentation for wording, clarity, and removing duplicate information.
- Added visual elements like graphs and flowcharts in technical reference to enhance content.
- Worked with documentation as code, following Git workflows.
- Built a documentation site from scratch with React-based site generator Docusaurus.
- Gained more experience with agile development and project management tools.

- Wrote product documentation designed for varying levels of technically skilled users.
- Created content from traditional tech reference to marketing copy.
- Coded applications to demonstrate APIs and wrote accompanying code guides.
- Reviewed and edited code and guides from the documentation team.
- Edited articles from the marketing team.

Stay-At-Home Parent, Bothell, WA

JUNE 2014 - FEBRUARY 2022

- Gained the ability to handle multiple competing priorities in a fast-paced environment.
- Honed patience into a skill to succeed in tedious, difficult, or even uncomfortable situations.
- Developed a love for teaching with the ability to adapt mentoring style to different personalities and learning styles.

Pier 1 Imports, Bellevue, WA — Sales Leader

AUGUST 2012 - JUNE 2014

- Frequently led my team to sales totaling 20% over our target.
- Provided excellent customer service, specializing in service issues and time consuming design projects.
- Coached and mentored up to 5 employees at a time.
- Adapted corporate directives and strategies to practicable goals and guidelines.
- Set new displays 4 times a year, starting from scratch and finishing in 3 days or less.

PROJECTS

MyLitLife | https://github.com/rsowald/MyLitLife

A web application to track reading lists and reading history. A user can find book recommendations as well as save reading notes, opinions, and ratings for each book.

- Collaborated closely with 5 team members to create a dynamic React user interface.
- Built reusable React components that could be used across multiple pages.
- Maintained a Mongo database with Mongoose models.
- Gathered, evaluated, and incorporated user feedback.
- Participated in code reviews to ensure high quality before changes were integrated.

Technology used — React, Firebase authorization, MongoDb, Heroku deployment, React Bootstrap, JS, HTML

Meal Planner | https://github.com/rsowald/MealPlanner | https://rsowald.github.io/MealPlanner

Search for recipe ideas by meal name and save your recipe links to a built-in weekly calendar. Meal Planner also has a random cocktail button that will present you a cocktail recipe to go with your meal.

- Created a stable, collaborative and supportive work environment with 4 peers.
- Researched and implemented new technologies including multiple REST APIs.
- Daily troubleshooting issues and problem solving as necessary.

Technology used — AJAX, jQuery, client local storage, Materialize CSS, JS, HTML

I Blog Technically | https://github.com/rsowald/TechBlog

Similar to WordPress, authenticated users can create, edit, or delete blog posts and write comments.

- Focused on the customer experience to create a streamlined UI with the Handlebars.js framework.
- Developed a robust SQL database utilizing Sequelize.
- Self motivated to meet and exceed expectations for the project.

Technology used — Node.js, Sequelize, Handlebars.js, Express, Heroku + Jaws DB, Bootstrap CSS, JS, HTML

EDUCATION

University of Washington Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp - Certificate

DEC 2020 - JUNE 2021

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node JS, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and React JS.

The Ohio State University, Columbus, OH — BA History, BA English

SEPT 2005 - JUNE 2009

Magna Cum Laude GPA 3.84